thewhole9.com 2014-05-01

# Online community for artists, graphic designers, writers, etc.: The Whole 9

The Whole 9 takes your privacy seriously and urges you to read our privacy policy carefully and to make note of your rights under this policy.

Changes to this Privacy Statement

From time to time, The Whole 9 may use customer information for new purposes not previously disclosed in this privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes here. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back to our Privacy Policy periodically.

**WHAT INFORMATION DOES THE WHOLE 9 GATHER AND/OR TRACK ABOUT YOU?**

Personally Identifying Information

The Whole 9 collects personal information when you register with us, when you use our services, when you visit our web pages or the pages of certain partners, or when you write or phone us. The Whole 9 may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies to better serve you, and to administer our business.

When you register we gather contact information (such as your name, phone number and email address) and demographic information (like your birth date, gender, zip code, occupation and personal interests). Should you choose to build a creative portfolio on The Whole 9, you may also elect to supply your address, work history, business name, and information about your training and education.

The Whole 9 collects information about your transactions with us and possibly with some of our business partners who act on our behalf to provide services to you. This may include information about your use of the services that we offer.

Anonymous Information

The Whole 9 also gathers anonymous information, which may be used or shared with third parties. This information does not personally identify you but may be helpful for improving the services we offer. Generally this information is collected through "traffic data" and may entail the use of "cookies," "IP addresses," or other numeric codes used to identify a computer.

Cookies: "Cookies" give users special, random IDs that are small text files, which are stored on the hard drive of a user's computer. The Whole 9 employs cookies to recognize you and your access privileges for certain locations on the Web site, as well as to track site usage. Subscribers who do not accept cookies from the Web site cannot access many areas of the Web site.

IP Addresses: The Whole 9 also logs IP addresses for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. (Your IP address indicates the location of your computer on the Internet.) The Whole 9 does not log IP addresses to track your session, nor do we link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable.

Credit Card Information: If you use a credit card to pay for The Whole 9 service, we may retain your credit card information in order to renew your account in the event you elect to renew your subscription. When we do retain credit card information, we keep it secure and separate from other demographic information you may have given us. We do not share credit card information.

**WITH WHOM DOES THE WHOLE 9 SHARE THE INFORMATION IT GATHERS AND/OR TRACKS?**

Personally Identifying Information

As previously stated, The Whole 9 takes the privacy of its customers seriously and, therefore, you have the ability to control how we use your personally identifying information by telling us if you wish to opt-out of certain uses of your information, as described in greater detail in the "Opting Out" provision below.

The Whole 9 may, on occasion, choose to share personally identifying information collected about subscribers with select trusted third parties who work on behalf of or with The Whole 9 under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your personal information to help The Whole 9 communicate with you about offers from The Whole 9. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information. If you prefer not to have your personally identifying information shared with select third parties, please see the "Opting Out" provision below.

Personal information about you as an individual subscriber may be shared, regardless of your "opt-out" status, if it is required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) comply with the law or comply with legal process served on The Whole 9; and (2) protect and defend the legitimate business interests, rights or property of The Whole 9, its users, advertisers, customers, sponsors, advertisers or affiliates.

Customer Requests for Personal Information: Upon your request, The Whole 9 will provide you with its record of the personal information you gave us at registration. For security reasons, this information will only be sent to the e-mail address on file for the subscriber ID associated with it.

Correspondence with The Whole 9: If you send us personal correspondence, such as e-mails or letters, or if other users or third parties send correspondence to The Whole 9 about your activities or postings on the Web site, The Whole 9 may collect such information into a file specific to you. All submissions become property of The Whole 9.

Anonymous Information

The Whole 9 also shares the information it gathers in a compiled format with advertisers and other partners. The compiled format does not include personally identifying information.

**WHAT DOES THE WHOLE 9 DO WITH THE INFORMATION IT GATHERS AND/OR TRACKS?**

Data Security: To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online, including SSL security for credit card submissions.

Account Maintenance: The Whole 9 may utilize the contact information you provided at registration, such as your telephone number and e-mail address, to contact you regarding account status, changes to the subscriber agreement, and to confirm registration.

Service Updates and Email Promotions: Using the contact information and email addresses provided at registration, The Whole 9 periodically sends promotional messages to its users about services offered by The Whole 9 and notifies users of new features or changes that may be made to these services.

The Whole 9 may also elect to send promotional messages on behalf of selected third parties whose products or services we think may be of interest to you. If you prefer not to receive promotional e-mails from The Whole 9, please see the "Opting Out" provision below.

THIRD PARTY PARTNERS AND LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES  
  
The Whole 9 is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of Web sites to which it may link. This policy applies solely to information collected by The Whole 9.

The Whole 9 Provider Partner Products & Services: While visiting the Web site, you may decide to purchase a product or service through one of our provider partners whose services are promoted or advertised on the site. If you do so, you will be acting under the guidelines of the third party provider's privacy policy, if it has one. The Whole 9 cannot make guarantees or a warranty as to the nature of a third party’s use of your personal information.

OPTING-OUT, CORRECTIONS AND CANCELLATIONS

If you are already a registered user with The Whole 9, you may manage your promotional e-mail preferences by "opting-out" of further email contact from The Whole 9 (excepting notification of major changes to the service) directly by logging in, going to Account Information and selecting which emails you would like to receive under EMAIL OPTIONS.

You may also correct information that is no longer accurate or delete your account completely on this page. If you have additional questions, please go to CONTACT US, or please contact:

**The Whole 9  
Attn: Member Services  
6101 Washington Blvd.  
Culver City, CA 90232 USA**
